Joseph F. Rodgers Business Records, 1891-1902
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Joseph F. Rodgers Business Records, 1891-1902
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
221-230
10 boxes (5 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert McCaslin, 1990. Found in his attic at 222 South Fairfax Street.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joseph F. Rodgers (December 27, 1853 - August 31, 1937) was a carpenter, builder and contractor in Alexandria in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. He was born in Fairfax County, Virginia, and his father's name was Lorenzo Rodgers. Joseph's wife's name was Willie, and they had children by the names of Raymond, Ruth and Nevelle.
The Rodgers lived at different addresses in Alexandria including 222 South Fairfax Street and 313 South Lee Street. The Fairfax address and 307 Prince Street were also listed as business addresses for Joseph Rodgers in Alexandria City Directories.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of bills and receipts relating to Joseph Rodgers' contracting and personal business dealings in Old Town Alexandria. Examples include letterhead receipts from Weadon Brothers Hardware, Paints, Oils Glass and Guns; George Ayers...Dealer in Wheels; Isaac Eichberg Foreign and Domestic Dry Goods; Smoot Lumber; Curtin and Butts Alexandria Iron Works, and many other local businesses. Also includes building permits.
Original papers are in boxes 221-227; photocopies of the collection are in boxes 228-230. Patrons are to use photocopies since the originals are brittle and in poor condition.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Physical Condition
The materials were originally stored by impaling them on a steel hook for hanging. Patrons are to use the photocopies in Boxes 228-230 since the originals are brittle and in poor condition.
Index Terms
Business records; Independent contractors--Virginia--Alexandria; Rodgers, Joseph F. (1853-1937)
Contents List
- Records, November 1890 - October 1893. (Box-folder 221:1-23)
- Records, November 1893 - August 1895. (Box-folder 222:1-18)
- Records, September 1895 - March 1897. (Box-folder 223:1-15)
- Records, April 1897 - August 1898. (Box-folder 224:1-17)
- Records, September 1898 - October 1899. (Box-folder 225:1-17)
- Records, November 1899 - April 1901. (Box-folder 226:1-21)
- Records, May 1901 - June 1902 and year unknown. (Box-folder 227:1-16)
- Copies of records (6 velobound volumes), March 1891 - March 1897. (Box 228)
- Copies of records (6 velobound volumes), November 1897 - December 1900. (Box 229)
- Copies of records (2 velobound volumes), January 1900 - June 1902. (Box 230)